Guide to The Packer Collegiate Institute records 2014.019
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 23: Miscellaneous, circa 1850s-1999; 3 Cubic Feet in 14 boxes
  - Bates Collection and Auction information from Swann Galleries; Argosy Book Store correspondence, list of books, sale results, The Bates Library collection was left to the school in 1901 by Jane Bates in memory of his daughter who was a student at Packer and died in 1890 at the age of 16 (perhaps the most valuable book was the 1855 edition of Whitman's Leaves of Grass, the 12th issue of the 1st edition, partly printed by Whitman himself in Brooklyn., 1983-1999 (Box 381, Folder 4)
  - Morgan Guaranty – Brochure & Morgans contribution to the community, 1984 (Box 382, Folder 5)
  - Ride a Purple Pelican by Jack Prelutsky and Garth Williams, 1988 (Box 527, Folder 17)
  - St. Ann's admissions, circa 1990s (Box 527, Folder 18)
- Series 24: Upper School History Club COVID-19 oral histories, 2020-; 314 Gigabytes in 53 video files; running time of available interviews: 16 hours, 37 minutes, and 20 seconds. All recordings are born-digital.
  Arranged alphabetically by narrator's last name.
  This series contains thirty-two oral histories conducted during the COVID-19 pandemic by members of Packer's Upper School History Club with Packer staff, teachers, and students. The oral history interviews focus on narrators' experiences staying-at-home, or leaving Brooklyn, during the pandemic and how the pandemic impacted their lives. The first group of interviews were conducted from May 13, 2020 to June 1, 2020. The second group of interviews were conducted with twenty-one of the initial narrators six months after the first interviews from October 22, 2020 to December 3, 2020.
  - Oral history interviews with Jim Anderson, April 12, 2020, November 20, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interview, Jim Anderson discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted his life as the chief technology officer at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    These interviews can be accessed online at the Internet Archive.
    Coronaviruses; Education; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Anderson, Jim; Sadler, Sadie; Packer Collegiate Institute
  - Oral history interviews with Lynnette Arthur, May 17, 2020, November 23, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Lynnette Arthur discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as the preschool head teacher and preschool diversity and equity coordinator at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Coronaviruses; Education; Teaching; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Packer Collegiate Institute; Sadler, Sadie; Arthur, Lynnette
  - Oral history interview with Larissa Dzegar, May 13, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interview, Larissa Dzegar discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as the dean of the class of 2021 and an upper school English teacher at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    This interview can be accessed online at the Internet Archive.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Education; Teaching; Coronaviruses; Packer Collegiate Institute; Killackey, Amelia; Dzegar, Larissa
  - Oral history interview with Graham Hall-Keough, May 4, 2020, December 3, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Graham Hall-Keough, class of 2021, discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted his life as a student at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Coronaviruses; Education; High school students -- New York (State) -- New York; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Packer Collegiate Institute; Yohn, Nicholas; Hall-Keough, Graham
  - Oral history interviews with Jeremy Hawkins, May 21, 2020, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Jeremy Hawkins discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted his life as a middle and upper school health teacher at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Teaching; Education; Coronaviruses; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Packer Collegiate Institute; Topper-Kroog, Ariana; Hawkins, Jeremy
  - Oral history interview with Dio Hernandez, May 21, 2020, November 18, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Dio Hernandez discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as an upper school French and Spanish teacher.
    Coronaviruses; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Teaching; Education; Packer Collegiate Institute; Pridgen, Nathalie; Hernandez, Dio
  - Oral history interviews with Su-Ling Huang, May 29, 2020, October 28, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Su-Ling Huang discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as a middle school Mandarin Chinese teacher.
    Coronaviruses; Education; Teaching; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Packer Collegiate Institute; Sadler, Sadie; Huang, Su-Ling
  - Oral history interviews with Tom James, May 18, 2020, November 2, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Tom James discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted his life as the interim head of the math department, upper school math teacher, and upper school diversity and equity coordinator.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Teaching; Education; Coronaviruses; Packer Collegiate Institute; Sadler, Sadie; James, Tom
  - Oral history interviews with Todd Johnson, May 6, 2020, November 17, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Todd Johnson discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted his life as a middle and upper school English teacher.
    Education; Coronaviruses; Teaching; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Packer Collegiate Institute; Sadler, Sadie; Johnson, Todd
  - Oral history interview with Monika Johnston, May 17, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interview, Monika Johnston discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as the head of the history department and an upper school history teacher.
    Coronaviruses; Teaching; Education; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Packer Collegiate Institute; Sadler, Sadie; Johnston, Monika
  - Oral history interview with Heelah Karim, May 31, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interview, Heelah Karim, class of 2022, discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as a student at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Coronaviruses; Education; High school students -- New York (State) -- New York; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Packer Collegiate Institute; Topper-Kroog, Ariana; Karim, Heelah
  - Oral history interviews with Craig Kennedy, May 18, 2020, November 19, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Craig Kennedy discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted his life as the superintendent of buildings and grounds at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Coronaviruses; Education; Buildings -- New York (State) -- Kings County -- Maintenance and repair; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Packer Collegiate Institute; Sadler, Sadie; Kennedy, Craig
  - Oral history interview with Rebekah Kim, May 21, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interview, Rebekah Kim, class of 2021, discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as a student at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Coronaviruses; Education; High school students -- New York (State) -- New York; Packer Collegiate Institute; Yohn, Nicholas; Kim, Rebekah
  - Oral history interview with Susannah Livingston, May 22, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interview, Susannah Livingston discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as an upper school history teacher at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Coronaviruses; Education; Teaching; Packer Collegiate Institute; Sadler, Sadie; Livingston, Susannah
  - Oral history interviews with Bridget Londay, May 20, 2020, November 13, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Bridget Londay discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as the head of the health education department and an upper school health teacher at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Teaching; Education; Coronaviruses; Packer Collegiate Institute; Pridgen, Nathalie; Londay, Bridget
  - Oral history interviews with Alice Lurain, May 15, 2020, November 20, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Alice Lurain discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as an upper school science teacher at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Coronaviruses; Teaching; Education; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Packer Collegiate Institute; Pridgen, Nathalie; Lurain, Alice; Anderson, Lucy
  - Oral history interviews with Li Ma, May 20, 2020, November 16, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Li Ma discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as an upper school Mandarin Chinese teacher at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Coronaviruses; Teaching; Education; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Packer Collegiate Institute; Pridgen, Nathalie; Ma, Li
  - Oral history interviews with Tamara Machac, May 28, 2020, November 20, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Tamara Machac discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as an upper school physics and science research teacher at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Coronaviruses; Teaching; Education; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Packer Collegiate Institute; Topper-Kroog, Ariana; Machac, Tamara
  - Oral history interview with Ann Martinez, June 1, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interview, Ann Martinez discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as a food service staff member at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Education; Food service employees; Packer Collegiate Institute; Anderson, Lucy; Martinez, Ann
  - Oral history interviews with Peter Melman, May 15, 2020, November 16, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Peter Melman discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted his life as an upper school English teacher and Packer parent to a sixth grader at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Coronaviruses; Teaching; Education; Parents -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Packer Collegiate Institute; Topper-Kroog, Ariana; Melman, Peter
  - Oral history interviews with Vidya Misra, May 13, 2020, October 30, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Vidya Misra discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as a middle school history teacher and middle school diversity and equity coordinator at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Education; Teaching; Coronaviruses; Packer Collegiate Institute; Sadler, Sadie; Misra, Vidya
  - Oral history interviews with Nicholas Morton, May 19, 2020, November 10, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Nicholas Morton discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted his life as the assistant director of middle and upper school admissions and assistant director of financial aid at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Coronaviruses; Education; Student financial aid administrators; Packer Collegiate Institute; Pridgen, Nathalie; Morton, Nicholas
  - Oral history interview with Maria Nunes, May 20, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interview, Maria Nunes discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as the head of the upper school at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Education; Coronaviruses; High school principals; Packer Collegiate Institute; Lapidus, Stella; Nunes, Maria
  - Oral history interviews with Danielle Ross, May 19, 2020, November 20, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Danielle Ross discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as an upper school math teacher at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Coronaviruses; Teaching; Education; Packer Collegiate Institute; Topper-Kroog, Ariana; Ross, Danielle
  - Oral history interview with Abraham Rothstein, May 30, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interview, Abraham Rothstein, class of 2021, discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted his life as a student at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Education; High school students -- New York (State) -- New York; Coronaviruses; Packer Collegiate Institute; Yohn, Nicholas; Rothstein, Abraham
  - Oral history interviews with Erin Schmitz, May 21, 2020, November 13, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Erin Schmitz discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as the independent science research program coordinator at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Coronaviruses; Education; Teaching; Packer Collegiate Institute; Pridgen, Nathalie; Schmitz, Erin; Anderson, Lucy
  - Oral history interview with Semeka Smith-Williams, May 24, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interview, Semeka Smith-Williams discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as director of diversity and equity and Packer parent of eigth and eleventh graders at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Teaching; Education; Coronaviruses; Packer Collegiate Institute; Anderson, Lucy; Smith-Williams, Semeka
  - Oral history interview with Lauren Scruggs, May 30, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interview, Lauren Scruggs, class of 2021, discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as a student at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Coronaviruses; High school students -- New York (State) -- New York; Education; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Packer Collegiate Institute; Yohn, Nicholas; Scruggs, Lauren
  - Oral history interviews with Meredith Whitehouse, May 21, 2020, November 24, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Meredith Whitehouse discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as an upper school English teacher at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Coronaviruses; Education; Teaching; Packer Collegiate Institute; Pridgen, Nathalie; Whitehouse, Meredith
  - Oral history interviews with Lea Wong, May 31, 2020, December 3, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interviews, Lea Wong, class of 2021, discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as a student at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); High school students -- New York (State) -- New York; Coronaviruses; Education; Packer Collegiate Institute; Yohn, Nicholas; Wong, Lea
  - Oral history interview with Christina Young, May 27, 2020 (Disk digital files)
    During the interview, Christina Young, class of 2020, discusses how the COVID-19 pandemic impacted her life as a student at Packer Collegiate Institute.
    Coronaviruses; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Education; High school students -- New York (State) -- New York; Packer Collegiate Institute; Pridgen, Nathalie; Young, Christina